Grandma!
外婆
Mom!
妈
How's my Dad?
我爸怎么样了
How is he?
怎么样了
He was fine when at table.
爸吃饭的时候还好好的
Then,
然后
then I pissed him off.
然后我就气他来着
And he, he...
他 他 他
he suddenly fainted.
他就突然就晕倒了
Why did you provoke him?
你气他干什么呀
[I didn't mean to do it.]
我不是故意气他的
I...
我
I just contradicted him...
我就是顶撞他来的时候
Don't blame her.
不怪她
It's all my fault.
不怪她都怪我
Your Dad had a headache this afternoon.
你爸下午就说头疼
And his blood pressure raised.
说血压高
At that time,
我当时
I should have brought him to the hospital.
我就应该让他到医院来
It's all my fault.
都怪我
All right, all right.
行了 行了
Calm down.
都别说了
Dad is under emergency treatment.
爸这不是还抢救呢吗
Mom,
妈
don't worry.
别着急
In medicine,
在医学上啊
the first 3 hours after the illness
有黄金抢救三小时的
attack is the golden time.
说法
Dad was sent to the operating room
爸一个小时之内
within one hour already.
已经进了手术室了
We shall believe in science
我们要相信科学
and trust the doctor.
相信大夫
So relax, everyone.
都别着急
I didn't mean to upset him.
我不是故意气他的
I didn't expect this.
我不知道
It's all my fault.
都怪我
All right, all right.
行了 行了
Stop crying.
别哭了 别哭了
Sister, my dear sister.
姐 姐 姐
I beg you, please.
我求您一事
Really.
真的
Please take Xin back.
你带着心心回去吧
And Mom, too
把妈也带回去吧
With your physical condition,
您这身子在这儿
it's not helpful for you to wait here.
守着也没什么用啊
Me and my brother-in-law will stay here.
我跟姐夫在这儿等着
If anything happens,
有事第一时间
I will call you immediately.
给你打电话
[Jia Haowen,]
贾浩文
[I'm not going anywhere.]
我哪儿也不去
I'll stay here and watch over my Dad.
我就在这儿守着我爸
Xin,
心
you and your sister are both expecting.
你跟姐都怀着孕呢
And she is just newly pregnant.
姐这身子还没安稳下来
Trust me and the brother-in-law.
我跟姐夫在 你放心
I said I'm not going anywhere.
我说了 我哪儿也不去
I'll stay here and watch over my Dad.
我就在这儿守着我爸
All right, give up persuading.
行了 你别劝了
Mom is definitely not leaving.
妈肯定是不走
And we ought to stay.
我们也应该在这儿
Even if we return,
就算回去了
we will not feel at ease.
心里头肯定也不踏实
Let's wait for the results and see.
等结果出来再说吧
Sister, sister.
姐 姐 姐
Before you came, Xin
你来之前这心心
kept mumbling over and over that
一直在念叨念叨念叨
she should be responsible for this.
她老觉得爸这事怪她
What's going on on earth?
到底是怎么回事啊
Nothing serious.
也没那什么
You tell me carefully.
你给我好好说
Well, my Mom visited us, right?
这不是我妈来了吗
She saw this
看见这个
caused by Xin.
心心弄成这样
She didn't like it.
我妈就不高兴
So she complained to Mom and Dad.
就找爸妈告状来了
Dad heard her words,
结果 爸一激
and criticized Xin, then...
就说心了 然后
Xin hurt you?
心心弄的
She didn't mean it, sister.
她不是故意的 姐
She was at her will every time.
她哪次不是故意的
Sister.
姐
What did she say?
都说什么了
Sister, Xin won't disclose anything bad.
姐 心跟妈能说什么呀
They did not mean to provoke Dad.
她俩怎么会气爸
Blame me if you want to.
要怪您怪我
I am the culprit.
根在我这儿
Really, it is really...
真的 都确实
Why do I blame you?
怪你什么呀
You got anything to do with it?
这事跟你有什么关系啊
You want to take responsibility for her?
想替她承担责任是吗
I tell you.
我告诉你
If Dad is okay, that's fine.
爸没事还好
If anything happens, as his children,
有事的话咱们做子女的
all of us are accountable!
一个都跑不了
Now you try to cover for her?
现在想着替她遮
Isn't it too late?
早干吗去了
When you spoiled her,
你惯着她的时候
you never
没想过
considered the consequences today?
会有今天的后果吗
You are perfectly right, sister.
对对对 姐 我错了
Yes, it's all my fault!
真的 怪我 怪我
I'm sorry.
对不起
If you are sorry, please stop
怪你 你就别在
buzzing around me now.
我眼皮子底下晃荡了
Go away.
一边去
Don't be angry.
你别生气
What I said
我说的
is rational, isn't it?
没错吧
Totally.
对
But now
但是现在
it not the proper time for argument.
不是说这个的时候
Take a seat.
坐一下 来
I can't sit down!
我坐不下呀
Just take a seat.
坐一下吧
I don't want to sit with them.
我不想跟他们坐一块儿
Doctor, what's going on?
大夫 怎么样
[The surgery went well.]
手术很顺利
[Fortunately, you sent him here it in time.]
还好你们发现得及时
The patient is currently
病人目前已经
out of life danger.
脱离生命危险了
[Thank you, doctor.]
谢谢啊 医生
[Thank you so much.]
谢谢 谢谢 谢谢
[We are extremely grateful.]
辛苦了您
Darling.
老公
It's okay.
没事
Don't cry.
别哭了 心
I'm scared to death!
吓死我了
It's okay. Don't worry.
没事 不怕
Alright, Xin.
行了 心
I'm scared to death!
吓死我了
Dad is fine.
爸没事
[Okay, okay.]
行了 行了
[Don't cry, Xin.]
别哭了心
All is well.
没事
Don't be sad.
高兴高兴
Don't be afraid.
不怕 不怕
All right, darling.
行了 媳妇
It's fine now.
没事
You are here.
姐夫
Mom.
妈
What did the doctor say?
大夫怎么说
The doctor said that it is normal
大夫说进重症监护室
to get transferred to the ICU.
是一个正常的
It is a process of monitoring
对病人术后的一个
patient after the surgery.
监控的过程
Dad will recover
爸 日后慢慢地恢复
progressively in the future.
就会好的
Wait,
不是
he...
这
he is in the ICU.
这都进重症监护室了
It's a normal procedure?
还正常啊
Look at your Dad.
你 你看你爸
He has many tubes inserted into his body.
身上插了那么多的管
In his lifetime,
他这辈子
he never
他都没有
had so many tubes inserted!
插过那么多的管
Mom, Mom, look.
妈 妈 妈你看
Those tubes
就那些管子
are connected to
它是连接
the monitoring devices.
那些监控设备的
They are for data collection.
采集数据用的
They are safe.
安全的
No worry.
不用担心
Why is it closed?
怎么关上了呀
Mom, it's okay.
妈 没事
Please leave and go home.
家属们都先回去吧
No visits allowed
患者醒来之前
before the patient wakes up.
不允许探视
Not allowed?
这还不让看
Meng'an,
姐
I don't want to go back.
我不想回去
I want to stay here with Dad.
我想在这儿陪着爸
[Xin,]
心
the doctor told us to leave.
都让回去了
And you are expecting.
你肚子还大
I am not going back.
我不回去
You go back.
你回去吧
Why are you staring at me?
看我干吗
My words don't count anymore?
连我的话都不听了吗
Mom is also here.
妈也在这儿
She has been up all night.
熬了一晚上了
She is also tired.
也累了
You send her back.
你把她送回去
Settle her down.
安顿好她
Can I trust you?
还能信得过你不
Sure.
能
Mom,
妈
Mom, let's go.
妈 走了
[Yunjie,]
云阶
You go back to grandma's home together.
你跟着也一起回姥姥家
Okay.
好
You need to go to school tomorrow.
明天还得上学呢
Let's go, Mom.
走吧 妈
We go together.
我送你们
Go, go, go.
走走走
You go back with Mom.
你跟妈回去
We'll come to pick you up
我们明天一早
early tomorrow morning.
就过来接你
Okay, let's go
好好好 走
Okay.
好了
Go.
走
Take care of your aunt and grandmother.
照顾好你小姨和外婆
Sister, take care.
姐 你辛苦啊
I'll come early tomorrow.
姐夫 我明天早点来
Okay, okay.
行 好嘞好嘞 好
Be careful on your way back!
你路上小心啊
[Don't worry.]
好 放心吧
For Dad's situation, the recovery
爸这个病恢复起来
will not be achieved in a short time.
不是一时半会儿的事
Doctors are all like this.
大夫都是这样
They always tell
总是把病人
the worst case of
最糟糕的情况
the patient to the families.
先跟家属说了
So don't worry too much.
你也别太担心
I need to go to the toilet.
我去个厕所
Okay.
好
Meng'an,
梦安
You are awake.
醒了
What's wrong with me?
我这 又怎么了
You fainted.
晕倒了
The doctor said that
大夫说你
it is because of the stress.
是你紧张
You are a little emotional.
情绪有些激动
My child,
那孩子
can we still keep it?
是不是 保不住了
There is still possibility.
还是有希望的
Darling,
老婆
it is just because of Dad.
你呢 只是因为爸的事
He is sick.
他生病了
And you are stressed out.
你才这样的
But now we must
但是现在我们一定要
take care of ourselves.
把我们自己照顾好
You must take care of yourself.
你得保重啊
So that we can
那咱们才能够
take good care of the Dad.
好好地照顾爸
Right?
是不是
Do you agree?
我说得对不对
Don't worry about it.
别的先别想了
But I'm just an ordinary person.
可我就是个普通人啊
I do not have grand ambitions.
我没有过什么宏图大志
I just want to have this baby.
就是想生个孩子
I just want a happy family,
家庭幸福
success in work,
工作顺利
and good health.
身体健康
Why is it so difficult?
怎么就那么难呢
I understand now that
我现在才知道
why everyone sends greetings
为什么过年过节的时候
in the festivals
大家伙发信息
saying
都说
"wish you good health,
祝身体健康
and everything goes well."
万事如意
They are not easy goals!
太不容易了
Don't think like that.
先别这么想啊
Give me a hug, honey.
老公 抱抱
I am here for you.
老公在啊
[Where is]
姐夫
my sister?
姐呢
She's a little tired.
她有点累了
I asked her to rest
我让她在休息室
in the lounge.
歇一会儿
Yes, yes. She's pregnant.
对对 她还怀着孕呢
You two go back.
你俩回去吧
Me and Xin will stay here.
我跟心在这儿守就行了
OK.
行
Then, we go back now.
那 我们先回去啊
Don't worry.
放心吧
If there's anything, call me.
有什么事你给我打电话
Rest assured. Brother-in-law.
好 好 姐夫
Okay, come on. Let me walk you out.
好 来 我送你
Xin, look.
心心 你看
How nice to have siblings.
有兄弟姐妹多好
Sister and brother-in-law left.
姐跟姐夫走了
We can take turns.
咱俩还能替个班呢
Take a seat, Xin.
心 你坐会儿吧
You didn't get much rest last night.
昨晚上你都没休息好
I just stand here.
我就在这儿站着
Don't blame me for what I said.
别怪我这会儿说这话
Siblings are necessary.
要有兄弟姐妹
When we are old,
万一咱俩老了
if anything happens,
有个啥事
they can discuss and support each other.
他俩还能有商有量
Is that so?
是吧
Dad was fine.
爸本来好好的
It's all my fault
都怪我不好
Don't worry, Xin.
没事 心
Dad is gonna be fine.
爸没事的
Where are we going?
我们回哪儿
Back home.
回家
Get changed.
换身衣服
Go to work.
去上班
You are going to work?
你还去上班
There are some works
有些事情
needs to be arranged.
想去安排一下
The baby...
这个孩子
I don't want it.
我不要了
You heard what
医生说的话
the doctor said.
你也都听见了
It's hard for Dad to recover as before.
爸很难再恢复到以前了
Xin is having a second child.
心心又要生二胎
I am the elder sister.
我是老大
This family
这个家
is counting on me.
我得担起来
I've thought it through.
我想好了
Let Lanxiang
让兰香姐
live with Mom and Dad.
住到爸妈那儿
In the future, you shall
以后你就
take care of the schooling of Yunjie.
管好云阶的学习
I take care of Dad.
我照顾爸
You should take care of yourself first.
你先把身体养好
As for Dad,
爸的事
leave it to me.
交给我
We are having the regular meeting today.
今天开例会
Where are you?
你到哪儿了
Everyone is waiting for you.
就差你了
[Sorry I'm late.]
对不起啊 来晚了
It's okay. It's all right.
没事 没事
Why are you late?
怎么还迟到了呢
It's not your style.
这也不是你风格啊
Something happened at home.
家里出了点事
Sorry.
抱歉啊
Your department
你们部门
needs a deputy director.
不是缺一个副总监吗
Mr. Zhou recommended one.
周总推荐了一个
Think about it carefully.
你好好考虑考虑啊
[Well, Director Xu.]
是这样啊 许总监
[Ling Meichuan is the deputy director]
凌美川
[of the marketing department.]
是我们市场部的副总监
She joined us three years ago.
来公司也三年了
In the marketing department
在我们市场部
she works with content department
一直是跟你们内容部门
all the way for liaison.
进行对接
[She is relatively familiar with]
对内容部的工作
[the work at the content department.]
也相对了解
[So]
所以呢
[she wants to transfer to]
就想去你们内容部
[your department.]
轮岗
Practice and learn.
锻炼 锻炼
What's your opinion, Director Xu?
不知道许总监觉得
Is that okay?
可以吗
Why not?
可以啊
Are you okay?
你怎么了
You look so pale.
你脸色怎么这么差呀
My father had a stroke last night.
我爸昨天晚上中风了
I am having an unstable fetal position.
我也胎位不稳
Before I came here, I got an IV drip.
打了点滴才来的
What?
不是
Then why did you come to work?
那你还来干吗呀
Arrange your works
你赶紧安排一下
at hand quickly.
手头的工作
Hurry up. Go home.
赶紧回家
Just say you are out
就跟他们说
to meet the client.
你去见客户了
Wait,
这样
later, I will
我一会儿
prepare two sick notes for you.
给你备两张病假条
If Mr. Zhang doesn't ask,
老张要是不问呢
I won't put them in record.
我就不入档了
If he asks about it,
他要是问
I'll tell him you are on a sick leave.
我就说你请病假了
Hurry up and go home.
赶紧回家
Take a good care of your body.
好好养养你这身体
When you feel better,
什么时候养好了
you can return.
你什么时候再来
Our health is the most important.
这身体是最重要的
Are you kidding me?
你开什么玩笑呢
Thank you, Rachel.
谢谢你啊 瑞秋
No big deal.
这都不是事
The matter of Ling Meichuan,
凌美川的事啊
you don't need to worry about it.
你不用放在心上
She has relations with shareholders.
人家是股东的人
For you, she is a just passenger.
到你这儿就是个过路的
She is destined to be the vice president.
以后人家是要当副总的
Then Mu
那阿木
has really no chance?
是不是真的就没机会了
Well, for Mu,
阿木的事
I can apply to raise his salary.
我可以给他申请加薪
But the promotion,
这升职的事嘛
we'll talk about it later.
等以后有机会再说吧
How's your Dad now?
你老爸 现在怎么样了
He hasn't woken up yet.
还没醒呢
What can I say?
你说你这
I feel sad for you.
我都替你糟心
[Our course is mainly...]
我们的课程主要是
Hello,
阿姨
the class is not over yet.
我这边 课还没结束呢
Can you leave later?
能不能晚点走啊
Wait for me, okay?
等我回来好吗
I'm sorry.
不好意思啊
Okay, it's fine.
好 没事
Mom's call.
妈妈电话
Wanwan,
婉婉
have you finished your homework?
你们作业写完没有
Yes.
做完了
Mom,
妈妈
I want to watch cartoons.
我想看儿会动画片
Don't you want to go downstairs
你们就不想下楼
to get stretched?
去活动活动
Or play frisbee?
玩一玩飞盘
You should rest your eyes.
该休息下眼睛啊
Yes!
想
Dear,
阿姨
please take them downstairs
你就带她们下楼
and take some activities.
去活动活动吧
Don't go too far. Just downstairs.
别跑远了就在楼下
Okay.
好
Let's go.
走
Your mother doesn't want a second child.
你妈不想要二胎
That's a good thing!
是好事啊
So you can enjoy the love
这样你以后就可以独享
of Mom and Dad alone.
爸爸妈妈的爱了
How nice!
多好啊
Not like me.
不像我
The love of my parents
我爸妈的爱呀
has been divided into two pieces.
都被分成了两半
My little brother takes the bigger one.
我弟占据了一大半
But I want to persuade my mother
可是我想劝劝我妈
to keep this child.
留下这个孩子的
Why?
劝什么呀
Are you fool?
你傻呀
You'll regret sooner or later.
你早晚都会后悔的
Look at me.
看看我
I already told you.
反正我把话放这儿了
Believe it or not.
你爱信不信
I've thought about
你说的这些呢
what you said too.
我也都想过
But I think
但是我觉得
the love of parents is not a pizza.
爸妈的爱又不是大饼
Can it be split that easily?
说分两半就分两半了
But their love is that much.
但是爸妈的爱就那么多
Children are troublesome.
小孩很麻烦的
When the baby is born,
到时候他一出生
he needs to be cared of inside out,
吃喝拉撒都需要人照顾
occupying all the attention of parents.
占走了父母所有的精力
No attention to you anymore.
哪儿还有空管你啊
Actually, now I feel
其实我现在
complicated in heart.
心里挺复杂的
My parents hid it from me before
之前我爸妈瞒着我
about the second child.
二胎的事情
I was quite upset.
我挺不高兴的
But,
但是
my mother suddenly told me that
我妈现在突然跟我说
she doesn't want Little Grape.
她不想要小葡萄了
I'm quite disappointed.
我还挺失落的
What is Little Grape?
小葡萄是什么
Little Grape is
小葡萄就是
the name I give it.
我给他取的名字啊
Stop.
打住
Don't give it a name.
不要取名字
Once you do,
这名字一取
you get attachment.
感情就深了
My Mom said my grandpa is sick.
我妈说我外公病了
She has to take care of him.
要去照顾他
So she may not want
所以小葡萄
Little Grape anymore.
她可能不打算要了
No way.
不行
I have to persuade her.
我得去劝劝她
For what?
劝什么呀
I just spoke to you so much.
刚才跟你说了那么多
All in vain!
都白说了
I can't be against my conscience, right?
那我也不能做违心事吧
I figure it out now.
我现在想明白了
I just want my Mom
我就想让我妈
to give birth to Little Grape.
把小葡萄生下来
If I don't persuade her,
我要不去劝的话
I will regret it in the future.
将来肯定后悔
You forget your backpack!
你书包都没拿
Leave it to you!
交给你了
Dad,
爸
will Mom, for real,
老妈真的
not have Little Grape?
不打算生小葡萄了
Your Mom is having a hard time.
你妈挺不容易的
And now
再加上现在
grandpa is sick.
外公一生病
She must be under a lot of pressure.
她肯定压力很大
A very hard time.
很辛苦
Especially for having a baby.
尤其生孩子的辛苦啊
It is not something we can understand
不是咱们两个说理解
simply by saying we can.
就能理解得到
We can never experience it personally.
也不能够切身体会得到
But I still want to persuade Mom
可我还是想劝劝老妈
to keep Little Grape.
把小葡萄生下来
This matter,
这个事
shall be your mother's decision.
让你妈妈做决定
Let's not disturb her anymore.
我们就不要再影响她了
I found you adults
我发现你们大人
are truly irresponsible.
真的很没有责任心
Mom said it is an accident.
之前老妈说这是意外
OK, I believe her.
好 我相信她
I forgive you.
也原谅你们了
I accept Little Grape.
我也接受小葡萄了
But now you say
可你们现在又说
that you don't want it anymore!
不想要小葡萄了
What a poor life.
小葡萄多可怜呀
Take a seat.
坐
Dad,
爸
I still want to try to persuade Mom.
我还是想再劝劝老妈
If I don't try,
不试试
how do I know it's not working?
怎么知道行不行呢
Are you afraid?
你是不是不敢呀
I'm not afraid.
我不是不敢
I am waiting.
我是在等
Although your mother
你别看你妈妈平时
is a little bit incompetent sometimes,
有点不着调
she is very kind-hearted,
其实她内心很善良
and very reliable.
也很能扛事
About having child or not,
关于生不生孩子这事吧
it is because that
也是因为最近
she's under too much pressure recently.
她压力太大
She didn't think it through clearly.
没想清楚
We should give her some time.
我们给点时间
She will figured it out by herself.
她就想明白了
Furthermore, isn't your mother a
再说 你妈是不是一个
a person of strong self-consistency?
自洽力很强的人
I do not express my opinion,
我为什么不发表意见
because I do not want to push her anymore.
就是不想再给她压力
Do you understand?
你懂吗
I don't want to emotionally
我不想在情感上
kidnap her.
再去绑架她
What kidnapping?
什么绑架呀
I don't understand.
我听不懂
I just want to persuade her, again.
我就是想再劝劝我妈
Tell her my opinion.
发表发表我的意见
At this moment,
这个时候
let's keep quiet.
我们就不要再多说了
No more persuading.
不要再多说了
Why I told you this,
我为什么跟你说这件事
it is because that you are
因为你也是我们
a family member of us.
家庭成员之一
In this matter,
这件事上
we should also reach a consensus.
我们两个也要达成默契
No more persuasion.
不再多说
We just watch and wait.
我们就等
Wait for her decision.
等她的决定
But I just want to talk to her.
可我还是想再跟她谈谈
What?
什么
Express my feeling.
表达 表达
Sister.
姐
You came so early.
你早就来了
It's useless for you to stand here.
你在这儿站着也没有用
If Dad wakes up,
爸醒了
the doctor will call us.
大夫会给我们打电话的
Didn't you come here early, too?
你不是也一早就来了吗
I want to stay with Dad.
我想陪陪爸
You're having a baby.
你这还大着肚子呢
Go home.
回家吧
When Dad awakes, I'll call you.
爸醒了我给你打电话
I am not going back.
我不回去
You are having a baby, too.
你现在不也大着肚子吗
Just sit and wait.
坐着等吧
Sit down.
坐会儿
What are you doing?
干吗呢 姐夫
Haowen.
浩文
Saving some money to Dad's account.
给爸卡上存点钱
Wait, you...
你 你这
It's done already.
我已经弄完了
It's done.
弄完了
How much? Let's split.
多少钱 我们两家分
Split what?
分什么分啊
Come on.
这这
If we don't split,
你不分的话 你
if Meng'an knows,
梦安知道了
she will not agree.
她可不答应
Don't worry about it.
什么答应不答应
We are all family.
咱不都一家人吗
Your family, my family. Agree, not agree.
你家我家 答应不答应
What's more,
再说了
after Xin giving birth to the child,
这心心生完孩子
The task of taking care of Dad
照顾爸的事
will fall into
不都落在
you and Meng'an.
你跟姐头上了吗
That's one issue.
那是一回事
This is the other issue.
这是一回事
What are you talking about?
什么一回事 两回事
No, no, no.
不不不
You, you, you...
你你你
Just go, you.
走吧 你
You go away, please.
你给我走吧 你
It's all my fault.
都怪我不好
If it did not quarrel with Jia Haowen,
要不是我跟贾浩文吵架
my mother-in-law would not argue with Dad.
我婆婆就不会去找爸闹
Dad would not
爸也不会
suffer all these now.
变成现在这个样子
It's all my fault.
都怪我
Stop blaming yourself.
你也别自责了
It's not your fault.
这事跟你也没什么关系
Yes it does!
怎么跟我没关系
Everyone said like this.
你们都这么说
Mom also said that
妈也说
it's okay.
说没事的
That's not your fault.
跟你没关系
I made such a big mess.
我自己捅了这么大娄子
I know whether
有没有关系
it is my fault or not.
我不知道吗
If it wasn't me,
要不是因为我
Dad wouldn't be lying here.
爸现在也不会躺在这儿
I am responsible...
就是跟我有关系
Listen to me,
听话
don't cry anymore.
不哭了啊
No crying.
不哭了
I feel bad.
心里难受
I know.
姐知道
But what I said is true.
但是姐说的是真的
There must have been something
爸的身体
wrong with Dad's health before.
肯定就是之前有问题了
If he was really healthy,
他要真好好的
can he faint because of anger?
能一生气就这样吗
It's just none of us
只是我们之前
found it out before.
都没有发现罢了
Don't cry.
不哭了
Relax.
乖
I feel suffocating.
我堵得慌
Just speak out your feelings.
说出来就好了嘛
You need to stay here tonight.
今天晚上你辛苦一下
Let's watch over
我们俩啊
tonight.
陪个夜
Let the sisters
让她们姐妹俩
go back and have a rest, OK?
回去休息休息 行吗
It is okay.
没事 姐夫
I am good on my own here.
我自己在这儿就行了
Or I can get someone
大不了从单位
from the company to help here.
找个人来陪着
No, no, no.
不不不
I have to be here.
我得在
So I can be assured.
我在我放心
Just lend me a hand.
你帮我搭把手就行
I talked to your sister.
我跟你姐商量过了
After Dad discharged from the hospital,
爸出院之后
Our whole family
我们全家
will move over
搬过去
to take care of Dad.
照顾爸
You are
姐夫
my role model!
我还真得向你学习呢
What role model?
学习什么呀
You're busy with work,
你工作又忙
and Dad needs long-term care.
爸这个病是个持久战
Someone must be around.
身边一定要有人照顾
But
姐夫
we should think positively.
咱事也得往好处想
How lucky Dad is!
你说爸运气多好
Fortunately, he received timely treatment.
幸亏咱治疗及时
Is Dad awake?
爸是不是醒了
Nurse!
护士
Dad.
爸
The stroke of Dad
爸这病让我
reminds me of my childhood.
想起我小时候了
When Dad was sick,
那我爸生病的时候
only my mother could take care of him.
就我妈一个人照顾
I was only 12 years old.
我那会儿才十二岁
I went home and stepped on the stool
我回家踩着板凳
to cook.
还做饭呢
All the relatives lived far away.
那亲戚都住得远
They could not help.
也搭不上手啊
I am so envious of Xin.
心心我多羡慕啊
She gets her sister to protect her.
这有啥事姐都出头了
I think,
我觉着
I hope Yunjie and Xiongxiong
我希望云阶跟熊熊
can have the support of younger siblings
将来长大时候
when they grow up.
也有弟弟妹妹给照应
It will be good.
多好
Yeah, sure.
是啊
It's good to have a big family.
家里人多还是好
Yeah, right.
对啊
Two kids in your family, two in mine.
你家俩 我家俩
That's eight members in total.
咱两家八个人呢
That's a flourishing family.
那枝繁叶茂
More people, more energy!
人多力量大
Who dares to mess with us?
谁敢惹咱啊
Right?
对吧
Dad is awake.
姐夫 爸醒了
Awake!
醒了
Hurry, go.
走走走
This way, this way.
这边儿 这边儿
Xin.
心
Dad woke up.
爸醒了
Why are you crying?
咋还哭了
He doesn't blame me anymore.
他不怪我了
He has forgiven me
他原谅我了
Don't cry. Don't cry.
别哭 别哭 别哭
Be happy, cheer up.
高兴 高兴
Haowen.
浩文
I was scared.
我吓死了
It's okay.
没事 没事
Let's get some fresh air.
走 透口气 透口气
Don't cry, my dear wife.
别哭了啊 老婆
Okay.
行了
He has forgiven me.
他原谅我了
Forgiven, forgiven.
原谅 原谅
Don't cry, honey.
别哭啊 媳妇
No need to cry.
哭啥呀哭
I'm happy.
我开心
That's good.
开心 开心
Alright.
好了
The doctor said that
大夫说
you wake up very quickly,
你能这么快醒过来
which means the condition is good.
说明情况很好
You can be transferred to a regular ward
应该 明后天
tomorrow or the day after.
就能转到普通病房了
I just called Mom.
我刚才给妈打电话了
She's on her way here, too.
她也在来的路上呢
She's fine.
她也挺好的
You don't have to worry.
你不用太担心
I think you will recover
我觉得你恢复起来
very soon.
应该挺快的
When you leave the hospital,
等你出院了
Yunjie and I will move back
我跟云阶就搬回家
to accompany you.
陪着你
How about that?
行不
What...
你
What are you saying?
你说什么呀
The baby,
生
Dad.
爸
Don't worry.
不怕
Dad is here.
爸在
Here.
在
No worry.
不怕
I will
爸
look after.
带
Your job.
你带啊
So you get recover quickly.
那你赶快好啊
How is Dad?
爸怎么样
Dad can't speak.
爸说不了话了
He asks me to keep the baby.
他还让我生
How?
我怎么生啊
He assured me not to worry.
他不让我怕
But how?
我怎么办
What should I do?
怎么办啊
The baby.
生
Dad's condition is stabilized.
爸情况都稳定下来了
He will be sent to a regular ward soon.
马上转普通病房了
After Mom and Dad finished talking,
妈跟爸说完话
I'll take Mom
一会儿我就把妈
back home.
送回家了
I'll stay here with my brother-in-law.
我跟姐夫守这儿
Don't worry, you two.
你们俩放心吧
Sister.
姐
Now Dad's awake,
爸醒过来了
we are more reassured.
心里面咱们也踏实了
Go back and rest, you two.
回去休息吧你们俩
Where's Xiongxiong?
熊熊呢
My Mom is with him.
我妈带着呢
Sister,
姐
can you
你
follow me back to my home, OK?
跟着我回我家好不好
Can you stay with me?
你陪陪我嘛
You should go back together.
你们一块儿回去吧
I'm not reassured either
你一个人在家
to leave you home alone.
我也不放心
Let's go.
走吧
Come on. The car is here.
走 车来了
Take care, sister.
慢点啊 姐
Take care, Xin.
心 慢点啊
Then you watch over Dad.
那你们看着爸
No worry.
好
Safe driving.
慢点开啊
[Okay.]
好的
Let's go.
走吧 姐夫
OK.
好
Your mother-in-law is at home with the kid?
你婆婆在家带孩子呢
Don't blame my mother-in-law.
你们别说我婆婆
She didn't know the injury of Haowen
她不知道浩文那个伤
is an accident.
是意外
So she came to argue with Dad.
所以才会去找爸的
Put ourselves in her shoes.
那将心比心嘛
If I were injured,
要是我受伤了
you, Mom and Dad,
你 你跟爸妈
will also find my mother-in-law
也会去找我婆婆
and stand up for me.
替我出头的
Right?
是吧
Now
这时候
you try to defend her.
想着替人家说好话了
Can't you just be nice
那你跟她相处的时候
to her when you are together?
就不能好好的吗
I was nice to her before.
我之前跟她挺好的
Really.
真的
I don't know why.
我也不知道怎么了
It seems that
就好像
since I became pregnant,
自打我怀了二胎之后
I couldn't get along well with anyone.
跟谁相处得都不太好
I think it must be
我觉得肯定是
because of the progesterone.
孕激素的关系
Maybe, after I deliver my baby,
没准我生完孩子之后
everything will be fine.
就好了
Dad is sick now.
爸现在生病了
Mom must be fragile, too.
妈肯定也很脆弱
So can you behave
你这段时间
carefully these days?
能不能踏实点啊
I promise,
你 你放心
I will behave well.
我肯定听话
You just go to work,
到时候你们都去上班
and do your things as usual.
你们该忙忙你们的
I have nothing to do at home anyway.
反正我在家待着也没事
After Dad leaves the hospital,
等爸出院了
I will take care of him every day.
我就天天陪着爸
I can hire a nurse for him.
我给他请护工
Give him massage.
给他按摩
Take him out for walk.
带他出去遛弯儿
If one nurse is not enough,
一个护工不够
I'll get two.
我就请两个
I'll buy Dad
我再给爸买一个
an advanced electric wheelchair.
高级电动轮椅
So he can go wherever he wants.
他想去哪儿去哪儿
Travel to anywhere
想去哪儿旅游
he wants.
去哪儿旅游
He can go out easily.
出去玩都不耽搁
In that case
这样的话
the courtyard of Mom and Dad
爸妈那个小院
shall carry out barrier-free renovation.
要进行无障碍改造
So does my villa.
我的别墅也要改造
Or we sell it and buy a large apartment.
不行就换成一个大平层
No steps in the home.
带台阶的都不行
Right?
是吧
Let me think about the designing.
我想想怎么个设计法
Dad is just inarticulate for now.
爸现在是口齿不清
It doesn't mean he needs wheelchair.
不是非要坐轮椅
Yes.
对
Yes, he is inarticulate.
对 是口齿不清
Why did it happen to him?
他怎么就口齿不清了呢
He's so talkative.
他这么健谈一老头
How can he chat with others in the future?
以后怎么跟人聊天呀
It can be improved with rehabilitation.
可以做康复训练
He will be okay.
肯定会好的
By the way,
对了
what did Dad tell you
刚才在病房
in the ward just now?
爸跟你说什么了
Nothing.
没说什么
I couldn't hear it clearly.
听不清
Mom.
妈
The big sister has come.
大姐来了
How is your father?
你爸爸现在怎么样了
He has woken up.
人已经醒过来了
Fortunately Haowen
要说还得是浩文
sent him to hospital immediately.
第一时间把他送过去了
The doctor also said
大夫也说
that the rescue was prompt.
就是抢救得及时
Great.
太好了
That's great.
这就太好了
Thank you, Meng'an.
谢谢大姐哈
Our Haowen,
我们家浩文哪
has to thank you for the support.
多亏了你们家帮衬
Otherwise, he won't have been able to live
要不然也过不上
such a good life.
这么好的日子啊
Don't say that.
您可别这么说
It is Haowen's own efforts.
还是浩文自己努力呢
Well,
那个
please focus on your family recently.
最近你们就忙家里的事
Leave Xiongxiong to me.
熊熊交给我
I am his grandmother.
我是亲奶奶
You can trust me.
放心啊
Don't let him play with his phone.
你别让他玩手机啊
How should you speak like that?
怎么跟你婆婆说话呢
Thank you so much, Mom.
你费心了 妈
Then you take a rest.
那你 你们坐会儿
I'm going to check on Xiongxiong.
我去看看熊熊啊
OK.
好
No hurry.
那您慢点
I don't want to comment on
你这情商
your emotional intelligence.
是有多低
[Wanzhen,]
婉真
our group
咱们集团
is marching into the financial industry.
也进军金融行业了
These are the financial products
这是咱们公司的
of our company.
理财产品
And the sales of financial products
而且理财的销售额
belong to your performances.
也是你们的业绩啊
Look,
你看看
your sales are pretty good recently.
你最近的销售额不错啊
You can take part of
你可以拿出来
the sales commissions
一部分销售提成
and convert them to
转换成
the financial products of same values.
同额度的理财产品
You will get high profit.
收益很高的
Mr. Qian,
钱总
We are a real estate company.
我们是做房地产的
Selling financial products...
这个金融理财
I think we need certain qualifications.
这恐怕需要经营资质吧
Of course we have.
怎么没有啊
Our company
咱们公司
has a special financial department.
有专门的金融部
Look,
你看
as for your premium clients,
你把你那些优质客户
especially those who
尤其是近期
have no intention to buy houses recently,
不打算买房的客户
you can recommend them
你给他们推荐
the financial products.
这理财产品
The financial department
金融部门
will send special personnel to follow up.
会专门有人负责跟进
Isn't it more profitable
这不比你
than selling one house by another?
辛辛苦苦卖房合适多了
I prefer
我还是想
to sell the house one after another.
踏踏实实卖房子
So stubborn.
死脑筋
Tonight
等晚上
I'll introduce you to some
我给你介绍几个
colleagues in the financial department.
金融部的同事认识
Wanzhen,
婉真
at last dinner
上次晚饭
you showed us your competency.
你可露了一小手
You should take advantage of the victory.
那你得乘胜追击啊
No, not tonight.
今天晚上可不行
I have to take my children to the class.
我得陪孩子上补习班呢
I can go.
我能去啊
I am available.
我有时间
Then you can talk.
那你们聊
I have some work to do.
我先忙去了
OK.
好的
Is this financial product
这个金融产品
that profitable?
收益这么高吗
The higher the principal, the more profit.
你本金多 收益就高啊
And if I recommend more clients,
那推荐客户
I can get extra commission?
还能有另外的提成
Higher than selling the house, for sure.
那肯定比卖房高多了
Mr. Qian,
钱总
Then I will follow you to make fortune.
那我继续跟您发大财呗
Why not.
行
Then, perform well at dinner this time.
那你晚饭好好表现啊
You already know
我这酒量
my drinking competency.
您又不是不知道
Go ahead, get ready.
行 去准备准备吧
Thank you, Mr. Qian.
谢钱总